<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Etsub Feleke</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Etsub Feleke</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:18:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Predictive modeling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/predictive_modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 14:18:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/predictive_modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-to-predict-housing-market-trends-with-machine-learning&#34;&gt;Learning to Predict Housing Market Trends with Machine Learning&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the competitive world of real estate, understanding market trends and forecasting sales performance can lead to smarter investment decisions and better risk planning. As part of my self-guided learning in predictive modeling, I explored housing market data to simulate the kind of analysis a real estate analytics team might perform.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Using a global housing market dataset from Kaggle (2015–2024), I applied machine learning techniques to build models that could forecast sales trends and surface key drivers of market movement. The goal was to push beyond theory and create something with real-world relevance—and showcase how data science can inform strategic decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping with Beautiful Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/web_scraping/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 14:51:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/web_scraping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;exploring-web-scraping-with-beautiful-soup-and-requests-a-learning-journey&#34;&gt;Exploring Web Scraping with Beautiful Soup and Requests: A Learning Journey&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Understanding web scraping techniques is essential for data science. The goal was to extract structured data from a real-world website, specifically focusing on the World Economic Forum&amp;rsquo;s Wikipedia page. This hands-on experience allowed me to learn how to programmatically interact with web content and parse HTML to gather information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-tools-requests-and-beautiful-soup&#34;&gt;The Tools: Requests and Beautiful Soup&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I chose to use two powerful Python libraries for this project: &lt;code&gt;requests&lt;/code&gt; for making HTTP requests to fetch web pages, and &lt;code&gt;BeautifulSoup&lt;/code&gt; for parsing the HTML content.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
